Hello and welcome to world news today.
If you're looking for a new adventure,
and have tens of thousands of dollars to spare,
from next year you could book yourself a trip
on the international space station. Earlier
on Friday NASA announced it will open up the
international space station for tourism and other
business ventures. There will also be up to two
short private missions per year. We are enabling
private astronaut missions to the international
space station. NASA will support up to two short
duration private astronaut missions per year to
the international space station beginning as early
as 2020. These missions will be privately funded,
dedicated commercial space flights allowing
approved commercial activities to be conducted
on board the stations. So now you know. Well,
Keith Cowing is an astrobiologist, former NASA
employee who now edits the online blog NASA Watch.
Well, Keith, what do you make of this? Well,
it is not surprising, NASA has had, or rather the
space station has had, commercial visitors before,
but it was always done through the Russians,
and it was sort of an ad-hoc sort of thing.
Now NASA has decided to clarify what it would
take to send, not only astronauts, but many
other commercial things to the space station and
the difference is that it is really clear now,
it’s like having a brochure to go to a resort,
you can tick off the things that you want to do,
and then you write a check. So, what is the
incentive for doing it? Is to bring more private
money into space research? Well, there’s a variety
of things, so there has been an interest in
commercializing the space station for many years.
Recently, with the announcement of NASA’s plans
to go back to the moon, NASA has been looking
for ways to offset some of its existing costs,
although President Trump tweeted today that NASA
shouldn’t be talking about going back to the moon,
so, who knows, but it may have just changed,
but that said, the though is that if you can
move some of the regular routine things that we do
closer to earth and then take some of funds saved,
give those to NASA, they can go back to the
old exploring a new frontier sort of thing. So,
it is sort of trying to re-balance the payments
to get back to a bigger plan of exploration.